Andrew Neece

Albany, TX 76430 | 325-370-0705 | dneece5@aggienetwork.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio url

FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

Fullstack Developer with a background in engineering and with knowledge of various softwares and programming languages. Previous experience in the civil engineering industry and graduating from General Assembly's Software Engineering Bootcamp with a desire to break into the Tech industry as a Software Engineer.

TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, Python, EJS, DTL **Libraries and Frameworks:** React, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma

Databases and other: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, RESTful Routing, JSON API

Interpersonal skills: dependability, leadership, creative thinker, teamwork, work ethic

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Pyramid - GitHub | App - JavaScript, HTML, CSS

A holiday themed, addition-based solitaire card game, users can sit back and relax and see if you can clear the Pyramid.

- Created card game using a card deck library in CSS and flexbox to design a christmas tree shaped pyramid.
- Used JavaScript to implement game logic that handles clicks, checks card values, checks winning and losing conditions, and shuffling mechanics that guarantees a unique game every time.

2k Create-A-Team - GitHub | App - JavaScript, CSS, EJS, Node, Express, MongoDB

One sentence about what the app does, think of this like a one-line marketing pitch

- Bullet points that describe the features you created in your app. Use the formula:
- Action verb + what you did + result
- Action verb + what you did + result

EXPERIENCE

Enprotec / Hibbs & Todd, Civil Engineer

Granbury, TX, 01/2021 - 11/2022

- Performed a wide variety of work under Civil, Environmental, and Process Engineering Managers including Engineering Feasibility Reports, water/wastewater system improvement designs, and Environmental Site Assessments.
- Led or assisted on 10+ water & sewer system design projects using AutoCAD/Civil3D and BlueBeam, and one of few in the company who is experienced in hydraulic modeling in InfoWater Pro.
- Participated in meetings and presentations with clients who consist of various utility districts in Texas and used Microsoft Excel for calculations and analysis of data for said clients.

Senior Capstone Project, Hardware & Assistant Software Engineer

College Station, TX, 01/2020 - 12/2020

- Worked on and completed a yearlong final project at Texas A&M as the lead Hardware Engineer and assistant Software Engineer on a team of 4 to test a classified method of cyber security for the Department of Defense (DOD) and Texas Instruments (TI).
- Designed a closed-loop, climate-controlled environment to run various tests inside of and analyzed the results at varying temperatures and humidity.
- Oversaw research, design, and development of two PCBs using Altium Designer. One to run the cyber security tests, and the other to control the climate-controlled environment.
- Assisted in programming a heating device, humidifier, temperature sensor, relative humidity sensor, JTAG and UART I/O pins, and SD card reader using C coding language. C# in Windows' Visual Studio was used for the Graphical User Interface (GUI).

Enprotec / Hibbs & Todd, Civil Engineer Intern

Abilene, TX, 05/2019 - 08/2020

- Used fluid mechanics to design a water tower and ground storage tank for the cities of Stamford and Mason, TX, and reviewed design plans for numerous projects.
- Audited three cities' Alternative Capacity Requirement (ACR) to submit reports to TCEQ using the daily water usage of each city from 3-5 years of data.
- Calculated Cost and Quantity estimates for multiple projects and helped with writing different technical reports and applications.

EDUCATION

General Assembly Remote, Certificate Expected: 03/2023

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

Texas A&M University, B.S. Multidisciplinary Engineering Technology

College Station, TX, Graduated: 12/2020